Speaker 1: Biden's new job numbers are out, and they are ugly.
Speaker 1: In short, real jobs are down, while DoorDash and government jobs are the entire Bidenomics
Speaker 1: miracle.
Speaker 1: My colleague EJ and Tony broke it down in a Twitter thread, so let's dig in.
Speaker 1: Headline jobs rose 209,000 in the June report, which was 30,000 less than expected, so that's
Speaker 1: a mess.
Speaker 1: That's also the lowest in two and a half years, and it took the unemployment rate to
Speaker 1: 3.6%, which is up just a smidge on the year.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, the previous two months were revised down by 110,000 jobs.
Speaker 1: By the way, we've seen this every report this year with numbers being revised down, meaning
Speaker 1: either government statisticians are getting very bad at their job, or they are intentionally
Speaker 1: reporting rosy numbers, then revising them down when nobody is looking.
Speaker 1: So accounting for the revisions leaves about 100,000 jobs on the month.
Speaker 1: Keep in mind, population growth cancels about 70,000 of those, leaving 30,000, essentially
Speaker 1: flat on a worker population of 162 million.
Speaker 1: But it gets worse.
Speaker 1: For starters, most of those net jobs were actually government jobs, which don't grow the economy.
Speaker 1: In fact, many shrink it.
Speaker 1: We can debate whether an EPA bureaucrat cancels 5 or 10 workers, but they certainly aren't growing
Speaker 1: anything.
Speaker 1: They are parasites.
Speaker 1: So that takes us to productive jobs growing actually below the pace of population.
Speaker 1: Finally, the big one, job composition.
Speaker 1: The BLS reported that multiple job holders rose an amazing 233,000 on the month, which completely
Speaker 1: swamped the alleged job gains.
Speaker 1: In addition, 452,000 more people were working part-time for, quote, economic reasons.
Speaker 1: In other words, not by choice, which BLS attributes to people whose, quote, hours were reduced due
Speaker 1: to slack work or business conditions.
Speaker 1: In other words, companies are reducing hours, which is the next step to layoffs.
Speaker 1: Take it together, and real jobs plunged by over 100,000 with more to come, while Americans made
Speaker 1: up the difference delivering DoorDash, not even counting the 2 million-plus workers who
Speaker 1: are still missing.
Speaker 1: I've mentioned in previous videos that they've dropped out of the labor force since COVID.
Speaker 1: Many are now on government benefits, where they're no longer counted as unemployed.
Speaker 1: Statistically, they're retired.
Speaker 1: So what's next?
Speaker 1: Erosion and job composition is hitting wages, which came in flat after inflation.
Speaker 1: That's actually surprising, since inflation was supposed to have trickled into wages by now.
Speaker 1: I've got an upcoming video on that.
Speaker 1: Even so, flat wages is bad news for the Fed, who's trying to make wages go down so people
Speaker 1: stop spending and the federal government can spend instead.
Speaker 1: So expect the Fed to turn this into yet more rate hikes, limited at this point only by their
Speaker 1: fear of crashing yet more banks.
Speaker 1: Month by month, Americans are losing their financial buffer, their full-time jobs, their savings,
Speaker 1: all while their debts pile up amid Washington happy talk about the amazing feats of Bidenomics.
Speaker 1: As post-pandemic pent-up demand fades and the economy drops into full-blown recession,
Speaker 1: on present trends, there will be millions of Americans up against the wall.
Speaker 1: Okay, we'll be watching.
Speaker 1: See you next time.